welcome to this first video about C
we are going to make our first program in C,
and we’ll call it hello world
hello world is often presented when you discover a new language
quite simply, we’re going to display “hello world” on screen
it’s a way to learn the syntax of that language
do not worry, in this video I won’t explain everything I type
just follow along, and everything will be fine
the first thing to know is that a computer program
before it can be understood by a machine
is a text file
which contains code in a certain language, in our case C
and can be read by a human
the second thing to know is that a program has always an entry point
in C, the entry point is called main
all right, let’s start
I have an empty folder and I create a file main.c
you can give it another name, the important thing here is .c
and inside there is a main function
so I type the main function  int main(), and brackets
how do you read this, int main is I declare the function
and in () what the function does
by the way a C file is always from top to bottom
so I have my file main.c
you can read it with cat
this the computer does not understand
how do I make it understand?
simply, I will compile it, I use gcc
gcc is a program that reads the .c files
and transform them into something the computer can understand
so gcc main.c, it worked
and now I see a new file called a.out
I can now execute it, as you can see here
it’s important to know that this a.out file is not a file that we can read
you see on screen, there are some things that I can’t understand
that’s normal, it’s binary, that’s how the computer can execute the program
after compilation, you can a file that you can’t read, but you can execute the program
so we wanted to display hello world
to prevent compilation problems, I need to add this
don’t worry, I won’t explain here, this will be covered in a future video
so the compiler will read from top to bottom
and it expects ; after each command
so her I type printf, printf is a command to display on screen
printf hello world
between quotes, ; at the end
now I compile again with gcc
I execute, and hello world is displayed
that’s good
and if I try without ; at the end
and again I compile it, I get this
it’s expecting a ; at the end
because this is what ends the command line
all right, going back
as you see there is the command prompt also displayed
what I would like is the command prompt on the next line
how? first idea is to put a line break here with Enter
but the compiler reads line by line
and on this line, parenthesis is opened, double quotes, and no ; at the end
and if I compile, I get error about no closing quotes
then some other errors
if you have problems, always look at the first error
because it may provoke other errors later on
all the errors that follow come from this first error
the quotes are not closed
I advise you to correct errors in order
so let’s go back to the prior version
typing Enter like that does not work
but there is a special character for a line break, \n
now if I compile again
oops I forgot to save
sorry, I compile again and execute
I have hello world with a line break
You read line by line, and a ; is the end of a command
for example, I could try to write the following
on this line I put two different commands
I asked to display hello pouet as well
I compile and execute
and it’s working
now if I delete this ; here
compile and execute
and here the compiler displays an error
a ; is missing between my two expressions
you should read what the compiler tells you
it will help you find your errors
my advice is not to put two commands on the same line
it’s a lot easier to read if you only put one command per line
I compile, and we have the exact same result
you can do this as much as you want
here I add a few, compile
you can see the result
we have made our first C program
and you know how to compile C programs
and have an executable to launch
in the next videos we’ll cover many other things
and you will perfectly understand what I did today
I’m sure that in a few videos, you will a C professional